SHARMIK HIRPARA

Software Developer

+61 452 512 791 | sharmik.hirpara@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

PROFILE

Disciplined and enthusiastic software developer with 2 years of experience as developer. As developer at TAL, maintaining and improving legacy software aligned with business requirements and clients' satisfaction. At Entrust ICT, refactored database and designed back-end and UI ahead of time and within the budget.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Developer at TAL, Australia

Feb 2022 – Present

- Developing reliable, usable software using **C#**, **.Net framework**, and **SQL** scripts, which meets business requirements within the required timeframes while minimising technical debt.
- Maintaining systems, processes, and documentation to deliver administrative processes and procedures effectively.
- Identify straightforward technical problems and find resolutions or refer problems as necessary.
- Involved in UAT testing, release planning, software releases and post release tasks.
- Delivering small administrative projects or the administration of larger projects so that all information is kept up to date and coordinated on behalf of the project team.

Freelance Web Developer, Australia

Apr 2021 – Mar 2022

- Updated, modified, and extended existing websites.
- Wrote clean, testable good quality websites using PHP, JavaScript, ReactJS, and WordPress.
- Collaborated with the clients and other stakeholders to build efficient and reliable features.
- Tech enthusiastic keen to learn new tools, technologies, and frameworks.

Software Developer at Australian Computer Society, Australia.

Apr 2021 – Jul 2021

- Wrote and maintained Java, and XML code to meet system requirements, system designs and technical specifications in accordance with quality accredited standards.
- Researched, consulted, analysed, and evaluated system program needs.
- Performed documentation support functions.
- Managed and coordinated Chatbot application team of 10 to discuss progress, team activities and agree on plans for the coming fortnight.

Web Developer Intern at Entrust ICT, VIC, Australia.

Aug 2019 - Oct 2019

- Wrote clean, well designed, efficient code using to best web development practices.
- Achieved project goal accurately and efficiently by applying data management skills while refactoring database.
- Designed and created the new website layout and user interfaces with standard PHP and JavaScript practices.
- Sharpened ownership and responsibility by reporting project progress and status to the supervisors using **Trello**.

Team Leader at Citywide, VIC, Australia.

May 2020 - May 2021

- Mentored and encouraged a team consist of 20 members.
- Generated comprehensive reports about team performance and shared to the supervisor.
- Created roster and delegated tasks.
- Listened to team members' feedback and resolved any issues or conflicts.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Object-oriented programming
- .Net Framework
- C, C++, C#
- SQL Server, MySQL
- Git, GitHub, BitBucket

- Java
- HTML, CSS
- PHP
- React
- WordPress

EDUCATION

Master's in Information Technology (Software Development), Swinburne University of Technology. Feb 2018 – Nov 2019

ACADEMIC PROJECT DETAILS

Snake-and-Ladder Game

Very basic childhood game, which can be played by 2-4 players for entertainment. This application was designed by using several Java APIs.

Language: Java, Object-oriented programming

Car Park Application

Car Park application allows user to display available parking slots. Managers can manage parking lot which includes adding, editing, and removing parking slot. This application was also tested through unit testing, integration testing and functional testing.

Language: Java, Object-oriented programming

Web application for Student Lab

To manage lab in universities, this application offers various features. Professor can create several labs and add students according to timetable. Application also stores the students' academic details to keep record.

Language: Java web server faces, JavaBeans

Interactive Dashboard for Smart Cloud Manager

Interactive dashboard for SCM helps user to track cloud resources and its usage. Application allows user to select data source and calculate cost savings based on usage.

Language: Python, R, ReactJS

COVID-19 Vaccination information

I am fully vaccinated.